Guide to the Mary McCarthy Papers, circa 1915-2013 (bulk 1960-1989)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
- SERIES I: WRITINGS
  - Published Books
    - Mask of State (1974 June)
      - Publisher's correspondence (Folder 53.7)
      - Reader correspondence regarding Watergate articles and Mask of State (Folder 53.8)
      - Clippings and reviews (Folder 53.9)
      - Reviews — clippings (Folder 301.2)
      - Corrected galleys (Folder 54.1)
      - Corrected proof [?]: "Postscript to Nixon" (Folder 54.2)
      - Watergate Notes: wire service copy (Folders 54.3 - 54.5)
      - The Observer, London, promo and McCarthy article, 1 July 1973 (Folder 54.6)
      - Marked copy of John Dean's statement to Senate Select Committee on Presidential Campaign Activities, 25 January 1973 (Folders 54.7 - 54.8)
    - Cannibals and Missionaries (1979)
      - Notes, 1974-1975 (Folders 55.1 - 55.2)
      - Notebook, 1975-1976 (Folder 55.3)
      - Notes and correspondence, 1978, 1979 (Folder 55.4)
      - Research material (Folders 55.5 - 55.7)
      - Research material (Folders 56.1 - 56.6)
      - Research clippings (Folders 56.7 - 56.8)
      - Research clippings (Folders 57.1 - 57.7)
      - Typescript variants: Miscellaneous (Folders 58.1 - 58.2)
      - Typescript variants: Chapters 1-3 (Folders 58.3 - 58.9)
      - Typescript variants: Chapters 3-5 (Folders 59.1 - 59.5)
      - Typescript variants: Chapters 6-8 (Folders 60.1 - 60.13)
      - Typescript variants: Chapters 10-12 (Folders 61.1 - 61.8)
      - Variants: rejected pages (Folders 61.9 - 61.10)
      - Chapter 6-8 variants, (photocopy) (Folder 62.1)
      - Draft as of June and September 1977, (photocopy) (Folder 62.2)
      - Chapters 1-12 [later draft?], (photocopy) (Folders 63.1 - 63.12)
      - Envoi [later draft?], (photocopy) (Folder 63.13)
      - Revised setting copy: Chapters 1-11 (Folders 64.1 - 64.9)
      - Corrected setting copy: Chapters 1-12 (Folders 65.1 - 65.12)
      - Corrected setting copy: Envoi (Folder 65.13)
      - Galley proofs (Folders 66.1 - 66.2)
      - Corrected galleys (Folder 67.1)
      - Editorial readers' queries and corrections; Cees Nooteboom's corrections; photocopies of illustrations; MM's summary of C and M; Acknowledgments; Boeing 747 control cabin diagrams; map (Folder 68.1)
      - Publisher's correspondence (Folders 68.2 - 68.3)
      - Dust jackets, promo material (Folder 68.4)
      - Reader mail (Folder 68.5)
      - Reviews (Folders 69.1 - 69.7)
      - Reviews — clippings (Folder 300.2)
    - Ideas and the Novel (1981)
      - Typescript variants: Chapters 1, 2, 4, (photocopy) (Folder 70.1)
      - Setting copy: Chapters 1-4 (Folders 70.2 - 70.5)
      - Galley proofs (Folder 70.6)
      - Galley proofs: marked set (Folder 70.7)
      - Galley proofs: author's pages (Folder 70.8)
      - Dust jacket and galley proofs of jacket flaps (Folder 70.9)
      - London Review page proofs (Folder 70.10)
      - Publisher's correspondence (Folder 70.11)
      - Reviewer's correspondence (Folder 70.12)
      - Reviews (Folder 70.13)
      - Reviews — clippings (Folder 301.1)
    - The Hounds of Summer and Other Stories (1981)
      - Typescript draft: The Hounds of Summer (Folder 71.1)
      - Typescript draft: The Appalachian Revolution (Folder 71.2)
      - Working proof and text for paperback covers (Folder 71.3)
      - Galley proofs (Folder 71.4)
      - Publisher's correspondence, 1962, 1966 (Folder 71.5)
      - Article: The Appalachian Revolution, The New Yorker, 11 September 1954 (Folder 71.6)
      - Article: The Hounds of Summer, The New Yorker, 14 September 1963 (Folder 71.7)
      - Reviews — clippings (Folder 300.6)
    - Occasional Prose (1985)
      - Typescript draft: Philip Rahv (Folder 72.1)
      - Typescript variants: The "Place" of Nicola Chiaromonte (Folder 72.2)
      - Typescript draft: The "Place" of Nicola Chiaromonte [Nicola Chiaromonte and the Theatre" - German translation], 1975 (Folder 72.3)
      - Typescript draft: Saying Good-bye to Hannah (Folder 72.4)
      - Manuscript draft: F. W. Dupee, (fragment) (Folder 72.5)
      - Lecture Notes: A Guide to Exiles (Folder 72.6)
      - Typescript draft: A Guide to Exiles — BBC talk, original version (Folder 72.7)
      - Typescript draft: A Guide to Exiles (Folder 72.8)
      - Typescript draft: A Guide to Exiles, final version (Folder 72.9)
      - Transcript: A Guide to Exiles, Expatriates, and Internal Exiles — BBC broadcast (Folder 72.10)
      - Research material and draft: Language and Politics, (manuscript) (Folder 72.11)
      - Typescript drafts: Language and Politics (Folders 72.12 - 72.14)
      - Research clippings: [Living with Beautiful Things] — "Art and the Value of Art" (Folder 72.15)
      - Typescript draft: [Living with Beautiful Things] — "Art Values and the Value of Art" (Folders 72.16 - 72.19)
      - Notes: Novel, Tale, and Romance (Folder 72.20)
      - Drafts: [Novel, Tale, and Romance] — "Narrative Techniques...and Their Implications", (typescript and manuscript) (Folders 72.21 - 72.22)
      - Typescript draft: Novel, Tale, and Romance (Folder 72.23)
      - Typescript variants: Novel, Tale, and Romance (Folder 72.24)
      - Typescript draft: Novel, Tale, and Romance — with letter to The New Yorker, 18 January 1983; (typescript draft) (Folder 72.25)
      - Research material: The Tolstoy Connection (Folder 73.1)
      - Typescript draft: The Tolstoy Connection, (2 versions) (Folders 73.2 - 73.3)
      - Typescript variant: The Tolstoy Connection, (fragment) (Folder 73.4)
      - Manuscript Draft: On Rereading a Favorite Book (Folder 73.5)
      - Typescript variants: [On Rereading a Favorite Book] — On Anna Karenina (Folder 73.6)
      - Typescript draft: [On Rereading a Favorite Book] — On Anna Karenina (Folder 73.7)
      - Typescript draft: [Acts of Love] — If on a Winter's Night a Traveler, (3 versions) (Folders 73.8 - 73.10)
      - Typescript drafts: Politics and the Novel (Folder 73.11)
      - Drafts: Politics and the Novel, (typescript and manuscript) (Folder 73.12)
      - Research material: [In the Family Way] — Marthe (Folder 73.13)
      - Typescript drafts: [In the Family Way] — Marthe (Folder 73.14)
      - [In the Family Way] Marthe - See also correspondence in 118.2.
      - Typescript drafts: The American Revolution of Jean-François Revel (Folder 73.15)
      - Miscellany: Without Marx or Jesus (Folder 73.17)
      - Research material: La Traviata Retold (Folders 74.1 - 74.3)
      - Typescript drafts: La Traviata Retold (Folders 74.4 - 74.6)
      - Typescript drafts: The Rake's Progress (Folder 74.7)
      - Research material and miscellany: The Very Unforgettable Miss Brayton (Folder 74.8)
      - Typescript drafts: [The Very Unforgettable Miss Brayton] — Green Animals (Folders 74.9 - 74.10)
      - Galley and corrected proof: The "Place" of Nicola Chiaromonte (Folder 75.1)
      - Galley proofs: On the Demo, London, The Times article, 8 December 1968, (Galley proofs) (Folder 75.2)
      - Clippings and correspondence relating to "On the Demo" (Folder 301.11)
      - Clippings relating to "On the Demo" (Box 389 (Oversize))
      - Galley proofs: F. W. Dupee — article, with publisher's letter, 23 January 1979 (Folder 75.3)
      - Galley proofs: A Guide to Exiles, Expatriates, and Internal Exiles (Folder 75.4)
      - Galley proofs: [Novel, Tale, and Romance] — Narrative Techniques and Their Implications (Folder 75.5)
      - Corrected galleys: [On Rereading a Favorite Book] — On Anna Karenina (Folder 75.6)
      - Corrected proofs: [Acts of Love] — If on a Winter's Night a Traveller, New York Review of Books article, 25 June 1981 (Folder 75.7)
      - Galley proofs: La Traviata [Little, Brown edition], with publisher's letter, 23 May 1983 (Folder 75.8)
      - Proofs: La Traviata [Little, Brown edition] with publisher's letter, 20 June 1983 (Folder 75.9)
      - Galley proofs: La Traviata [Little, Brown edition] (Folder 75.10)
      - Corrected galleys: Green Animals, House and Garden article, June 1983 (Folder 75.11)
      - Article: Philip Rahv, New York Times Book Review, 17 February 1974 (Folder 76.3)
      - Article: Saying Good-by to Hannah, The New York Review of Books, 22 February 1976 (Folder 76.4)
      - Article: F. W. Dupee, The New York Review of Books, 8 March 1979 (Folder 76.5)
      - Article: Novel, Tale, Romance, The New York Review of Books, 12 May 1983 (Folder 76.6)
      - Article: "The Tolstoy Connection," Saturday Review, 16 September 1972 (Folder 76.7)
      - Article: "Novel Choice: Mary McCarthy on Anna Karenina," The [London?] Observer (Folder 76.8)
      - Article: "The Lasting Power of the Political Novel," The New York Times Book Review, 1 January 1984 (Folder 76.9)
      - Article: In the Family Way, The New York Review of Books, 8 December 1983 (Folder 76.10)
      - Article: The Rake's Progress, The New York Review of Books, 5 November 1981 (Folder 76.11)
      - Article: "The Indomitable Miss Brayton," House and Garden, December 1983 (Folder 76.12)
      - Reviews: Without Marx or Jesus (Folders 76.13 - 76.14)
      - Reviews: Occasional Prose (Folders 76.15 - 76.17)
      - Publisher's correspondence and author's corrections: Occasional Prose (Folder 76.1)
      - Correspondence, 1971 (Folder 73.16)
      - Dust jacket dummy: Occasional Prose (Folder 76.2)
      - Original edited manuscript, pages 1-273 (Folders 316.4 - 316.9)
      - Manuscript copy, part 1, (Xerox MS) (Folder 316.10)
      - Manuscript copy, parts 2-7, (Xerox MS) (Folders 317.1 - 317.6)
      - Author’s corrected galley proof, p. 1-217 (Folders 318.1 - 318.5)
    - How I Grew (1987)
      - Typescript variants: Chapters 1-4 (Folders 77.1 - 77.3)
      - Typescript variants: Chapters 3-7 (Folders 78.1 - 78.5)
      - Typescript variants: Chapters 8-9 (Folders 79.1 - 79.7)
      - Typescript variants and notes: Chapter 9 (Folder 79.8)
      - Typescript draft: Chapters 1-9 [final version?] (Folders 80.1 - 80.9)
      - Chapters 1-6 (Folders 319.1 - 319.7)
      - Original edited manuscript, p. 1-100 (Folders 319.8 - 319.9)
      - Original edited manuscript, p. 101-245 (Folders 320.1 - 320.3)
      - Glossary by Carol Brightman (Folder 320.4)
      - Unedited manuscript, p. 1-245, (photocopy) (Folders 320.5 - 320.9)
      - Corrected page proof, p. 1-278 (Folders 321.1 - 321.3)
      - Corrected galley proof, p. 1-171 (Folders 322.1 - 322.4)
      - Galley proofs for the book (Folder 81.1)
      - Galley proof [for the Vanity Fair? article?] (Folder 81.2)
      - Proofs and publisher's correspondence regarding the 7 July 1986 The New Yorker, article "Personal History, pt. I,", 1983 (Folder 81.3)
      - Proofs: "Personal History, pt. II," The New Yorker article, 14 July 1986 (Folder 81.4)
      - Article: "How I Grew," Vanity Fair, March 1986 (Folder 82.1)
      - Articles: "Personal History: Getting an Education, parts I-II," ( The New Yorker, 7 and 14 July 1986 (Folder 82.2)
      - Reader correspondence, 1986-1988 (Folders 82.3 - 82.4)
      - Reviews (Folders 82.5 - 82.6)
      - Reviews — clippings (Folder 300.7)
      - Unidentified (Folders 322.5 - 322.8)
      - Annie Wright Seminary (Folder 323.1)
      - Early material autobiography (Folder 323.2)
      - Fragments, Chapters 1-2 (Folder 323.3)
      - Father’s letters and desk calender (Folder 323.4)
      - How I Grew fragments (Folder 323.5)
      - Fragments (Folder 323.6)
      - Notes for autobiography (Folder 323.7)
      - Article in Vassar Quarterly, 1988 (Folder 300.8)
    - Intellectual Memoirs (1992)
      - Research material (Folders 82.7 - 82.8)
      - Autobiography – Vol. II (Folder 324.1)
      - Frani Blough (Folder 324.2)
      - Variants of chapter 2 (Folder 324.3)
      - For Volume II of How I Grew (Folder 324.4)
      - For Volume II of How I Grew (Folder 324.5)
      - Manuscript - Autobiography - Volume II (Folder 324.6)
      - Volume Two (Folder 324.7)
      - Typescript variants: Chapter 1 (Folders 82.9 - 82.12)
      - Typescript draft: Chapter 2 (Folder 82.13)
      - Typescript variants: Chapters 2-3 (Folders 82.14 - 82.17)
      - Chapters 1-3 (Folders 325.1 - 325.3)
      - Forward by Elizabeth Hardwick (Folder 325.4)
      - Manuscript, p. 1-77 (Folders 325.5 - 325.6)
      - Manuscript preparation (Folder 325.7)
      - Master galleys, p. i – iv, 1-71 (Folders 325.8 - 325.9)
      - Master pages, p. i – xxii, 1-114 (Folders 325.10 - 325.12)
      - Autobiography volume 2, p. 63-78 (Folder 325.13)
      - Summary and beginning pages (Folder 325.14)
      - Unmarked pages (Folder 325.15)
      - Manuscript pages - various (Folders 326.1 - 326.2)
    - Reissues of earlier works
      - Reviews and other clippings (Folder 301.10)
  - Journal Articles by McCarthy
    - "Our Actors and the Critics, part I," The Nation — printed article, 8 May 1937 (Folder 83.1)
    - "The Actors and the Critics, part II," The Nation — printed article, 15 May 1937 (Folder 83.2)
    - "Two in Our Time," Partisan Review — typescript draft, Summer 1939 (Folder 83.3)
    - "The Company Is Not Responsible," The New Yorker, — printed article (Folder 83.4)
    - "A Filmy Vision of the War," Town and Country — printed article, April 1944 (Folder 83.5)
    - "Portrait of a Typical Negro?" New Leader — typescript draft, 13 June 1945 (Folder 83.6)
    - "The Iliad, or, The Poem of Force," politics — pamphlet number 1, 1947 (Folder 83.7)
    - "The Unspoiled Reaction" — typescript draft (Folder 83.8)
    - "The Unspoiled Reaction," Atlantic Monthly — printed article, March 1946 (Folder 83.9)
    - "The Season Was Good in Enfer This Summer," Town and Country, November 1946; (typescript draft - fragment) (Folder 83.10)
    - "The Season Was Good in Enfer This Summer," Town and Country, 30 January 1947; (letter) (Folder 83.10)
    - "Theater Chronicle: Sartre and the McCoy," politics — printed article, Winter 1949 (Folder 83.11)
    - "Greenwich Village at Night," New York Post series, February-March 1950; (typescript drafts) (Folder 83.12)
    - "Greenwich Village at Night," New York Post series — printed articles, February-March 1950 (Folders 83.13 - 83.22)
    - "The Vassar Girl" Holiday, May 1951 (Box 299)
    - "New Trends in American Education," The Listener — printed article, 24 July 1952 (Folder 83.23)
    - "The Menace to Free Journalism in America," The Listener — printed article, 14 May 1953 (Folder 83.24)
    - "The Revolt of the [American] Authors,", 26 Nov 1953; (typescript draft and printed article) (Folder 83.25)
    - "Thoughts of an American in England," The Listener — printed article, 17 June 1954 (Folder 83.26)
    - "Brunelleschi's Dome", (typescript draft) (Folder 83.27)
    - "Brunelleschi's Dome", Harper's Bazaar — printed article, September 1959 (Folder 83.28)
    - "Fiction Without Characters", Current — photocopy of printed article, May 1961 (Folder 307.1)
    - "General Macbeth", Harper's — photocopy of printed article, June 1962 (Folder 307.1)
    - "Madame Bovary", Tempe0 Presente — photocopy of printed article, September-October 1964 (Folder 307.1)
    - "Letter to a Translator: About 'The Group,'" Encounter — printed article, November 1964 (Folder 83.29)
    - "Mary McCarthy Ad-libs on Shakespeare's Women... " Vogue — printed article, [1964?] (Folder 83.30)
    - "Verdict on Osborne" — Advance proofs (Folder 83.31)
    - "Verdict on Osborne," The Observer, London — printed article, 4 July 1965 (Folder 83.32)
    - "Verdict on Osborne" — Reader correspondence and clippings (Folder 83.33)
    - "Lettre a mon traducteur danois", Preuves — photocopy of printed article, October 1965 (Folder 307.1)
    - "Conversation Piece" [transcript of a recorded interview with Janet Flanner], New York Times — typescript and photocopy, 21 November 1965 (Folder 83.34)
    - Books of the Year, The Observer, London — typescript draft, [19 December 1965?] (Folder 83.35)
    - "Mary McCarthy: Der Rod Der Literarischen Gestalt", Sinn Und Form — photocopy of printed article, 1966 (Folder 307.1)
    - "Les invention d'Ivy Compton-Burnett", Preuves — photocopy of printed article, February 1967 (Folder 307.2)
    - "Mary McCarthy reports from Vietnam", New York Review of Books — photocopy of printed article, 20 April 1967 (Folder 307.2)
    - "Mary McCarthy rapporto dal Vietnam", Tempo Presente — photocopy of printed article, June 1967 (Folder 307.2)
    - "Le Vietnam et les intellectuels", Preuves — photocopy of printed article, October 1967 (Folder 307.3)
    - "Was soll in Vietnam geschehen?" (with J. William Fulbright) Der Monat — photocopy of printed article, October 1967 (Folder 307.3)
    - "Vietnam: Solutions", New York Review of Books — photocopy of printed article, 9 November 1967 (Folder 307.3)
    - "Mary McCarthy uber Amerikas Krieg in Vietnam", Der Spiegel — photocopy of printed article, 1967 (Folder 307.3)
    - "On Withdrawing from Vietnam: An Exchange" (with Diana Trilling), New York Review of Books — photocopy of printed article, 18 January 1968 (Folder 307.4)
    - "Notes on the Election," The New York Review of Books — typescript draft, 24 October 1968 (Folder 84.1)
    - "La Situazione attuale in America" — printed article, [1968?] (Folder 84.2)
    - "Amig Vartuk, Hogy Elmuljon A Legiveszely", Nagyvilag — photocopy of printed article, 1968 (Folder 307.4)
    - "The Editor Interviews ... Mary McCarthy" — typescript draft (Folder 84.3)
    - "The Editor Interviews ... Mary McCarthy," Modern Occasions — printed article, Fall 1970 (Folder 84.4)
    - [Christmas Books], The Observer (London) — typescript draft and printed article, 1970 (Folder 84.5)
    - "Imagination, Anyone?" Newsweek — printed article, 10 June 1972 (Folder 326.6)
    - [Election 1972 — campaign issues], Newsweek — teletype and typescript draft (Folders 84.6 - 84.7)
    - Review of [Solzhenitsyn's August 1914], Saturday Review, 1972 (Folder 302.3)
    - "On Colonel Risner," The New York Review of Books — galleys, 7 March 1974 (Folder 84.8)
    - [Christmas Books], The Observer (London) — typescript draft and printed article, 1974 (Folder 84.9)
    - "Postscript to Nixon," The New York Review of Books — printed article, [October 1974] (Folder 84.10)
    - "Observer Christmas Books," The Observer (London) — typescript draft, 12 December 1976 (Folder 84.11)
    - "The End of Vietnam," The New York Review of Books — typescript draft, [1976?] (Folder 84.12)
    - "Vietnam," Le Monde — typescript draft, [1976?] (Folder 84.13)
    - "Books of the Year", Observer Review — photocopy of printed article, 18 December 1977 (Folder 307.4)
    - "Mary McCarthy: General Macbeth", Caiet — photocopy of printed article, 1977-1978 (Folder 307.4)
    - Harold Rosenberg memorial, New York Times — manuscript draft, memorial card, and clipping, 6 May 1979 (Folder 84.35)
    - "Christmas Books, 1978," The Observer (London) — typescript draft, 17 December 1978 (Folder 84.14)
    - "Jim Farrell," The New York Review of Books — typescript draft and printed article, 8 November 1979 (Folder 84.15)
    - "The Novels that Got Away," New York Times Book Review — typescript drafts and printed article, 25 November 1979 (Folder 84.16)
    - [Christmas Books], The Observer (London) — typescript draft, circa 1979 (Folder 84.17)
    - "A Divorcess on Gay Street: Meetings and Memories," Interview Magazine, January 1980 (Folder 393.4 (Oversize))
    - "Ideas and the Novel: Dostoevsky's 'The Possessed'", London Review of Books — photocopy of printed article, 17 April 1980 (Folder 307.4)
    - Observer Christmas Books 1980, The Observer (London) — typescript draft (Folder 84.18)
    - "Symposium: I Would Like to Have Written...," New York Times Book Review — fragment of typescript draft, 6 December 1981 (Folder 84.19)
    - "Pearl Harbor," Newsday — typescript draft, 7 December 1981 (Folder 84.20)
    - "Christmas Books - 1981," The Observer (London) — typescript draft (Folder 84.21)
    - "Green Thoughts: A Writer in the Garden," [review] New York Review of Books — corrected proofs, [1981?] (Folder 84.22)
    - "Lété des Rapaces," Playboy, French edition — proofs and printed article, May 1982 (Folder 84.23)
    - "Watergate Over the Dam," New York Review of Books — printed article, circa 1982 (Folder 84.24)
    - "A Burst of Pride," Newsday — printed article, circa 1982 (Folder 84.24)
    - "Love and Death in the Pacific," The New York Times Book Review — typescript drafts and manuscript notes, 22 April 1984 (Folder 84.25)
    - "Love and Death in the Pacific," The New York Times Book Review — typescript drafts, 22 April 1984 (Folder 84.26)
    - Chiaromonte – General, 1984-1986 (Folders 326.3 - 326.5)
    - Chiaromonte – The Paradox of History — postface draft, circa 1985 (Folder 326.7)
    - "Breeders, Wives and Unwomen," The New York Times Book Review — background notes and correspondence, 9 February 1986 (Folder 84.27)
    - "Breeders, Wives and Unwomen," The New York Times Book Review — typescript drafts, 9 February 1986 (Folders 84.28 - 84.29)
    - "Useless Freedom," Annandale magazine — typescript draft and manuscript biographical notes, [Spring 1988?] (Folder 84.30)
    - "Useless Freedom," Annandale magazine — clipping and proofs, [Spring 1988?] (Folder 84.31)
    - Letter with editorial notes regarding "Useless Freedom," Annandale magazine, 30 March 1988 (Folder 84.31)
    - "Theater Chronicle: A Touch of the Poet ...," Partisan Review — galley, undated (Folder 84.32)
    - "Letter to the Editor," Partisan Review — typescript draft and article, undated (Folder 84.33)
    - McCarthy on George Orwell — includes correspondence and clippings relating to George and Sonia Brownell Orwell (Folder 302.6 -302.8)
    - Miscellaneous McCarthy reviews of others' works (Folder 84.34)
    - Miscellaneous clippings (Folder 302.5)
  - Unpublished Works by McCarthy (alphabetical)
    - Comparison Between Italian and American Literary World — typescript draft (Folder 85.1)
    - For Janet Flanner — typescript draft, 1978 (Folder 85.2)
    - Good-bye to Martha McGahan — typescript draft, 1978 (Folder 85.3)
    - Harold Rosenberg — manuscript draft (Folder 85.4)
    - The Lost Week or The Caged Lion — typescript draft, 1945 (Folder 85.5)
    - Mr. T, Mr. and Mrs. A, the B's — typescript draft (Folder 85.6)
    - On The Siege of Krishnapur — typescript draft, circa 1974 (Folder 85.7)
    - Remembering Wystan H. Auden — typescript, 1973; (photocopy) (Folder 85.8)
    - The Ropes — typescript draft (Folder 85.9)
    - Fragments of miscellaneous works, (manuscripts, typescripts) (Folder 85.10)
    - Fragments of unfinished notes for essays and unfinished letters, (manuscripts, typescripts) (Folder 85.11)
    - "Mutualite", (typescript) (Folder 85.12)
  - Notes and Notebooks of McCarthy
    - Notecards for courses taught by McCarthy at Bard College and Sarah Lawrence, 1945-1946, 1948; (includes one card on projected piece of New Yorker fiction) (Folder 86.1)
    - Notes for study of New Yorker fiction, circa 1948 (Folder 86.2)
    - Notebook — Florence, circa 1955-1960 (Folder 87.9)
    - Notebook — Venice, circa 1955-1960 (Folder 87.10)
    - Notebook — Arthur Miller case, circa 1957 (Folder 87.5)
    - Notebook — Travel, Italy, 1958 (Folder 87.7)
    - Notebook — Miscellaneous observations, 1970-1978 (Folder 87.3)
    - Notebook — Solzhenitsyn's August 1914, circa 1972 (Folder 87.6)
    - Notebook — Mostly reading notes: Italo Calvino, Marthe, F.W. Dupee, Chiaramonte, and more, circa 1981-1985 (Folder 87.8)
    - Notes — German lesson (Folder 87.1)
    - Notes — Salzberg seminar (Folder 87.2)
    - Notes — Aspen Congress (Folder 327.1)
    - Notebook — Books on the Gothic (Folder 327.2)
    - Notebook (Folder 327.3)
    - Notebooks — French Gothic (Folder 327.4)
    - Notes — Journal, circa 1952 (Folder 327.5)
    - Notes — Nabakov letters (Folder 327.6)